<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hi, i&#39;m gianeen</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on hi, i&#39;m gianeen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Who Am I? Hi THERE!! My name is Gianeen hehehehe. Here is my mf resume</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>Projects Here are some coding projects I have recently completed for my Computational Bio class at UT during my Spring 2020 semester:
  Exploratory Data Analysis with Tidyverse Tools: Beyoncé versus Solange
  Modeling, Testing, and Classification of Beyoncé and Solange&amp;rsquo;s Music
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello R Markdown</title>
      <link>/blog/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>R Markdown This is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
You can embed an R code chunk like this:
summary(cars) ## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.4 Mean : 42.98 ## 3rd Qu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a New Theme</title>
      <link>/blog/creating-a-new-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/creating-a-new-theme/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This tutorial will show you how to create a simple theme in Hugo. I assume that you are familiar with HTML, the bash command line, and that you are comfortable using Markdown to format content. I&amp;rsquo;ll explain how Hugo uses templates and how you can organize your templates to create a theme. I won&amp;rsquo;t cover using CSS to style your theme.
We&amp;rsquo;ll start with creating a new site with a very basic template.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>(Hu)go Template Primer</title>
      <link>/blog/goisforlovers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/goisforlovers/</guid>
      <description>Hugo uses the excellent go html/template library for its template engine. It is an extremely lightweight engine that provides a very small amount of logic. In our experience that it is just the right amount of logic to be able to create a good static website. If you have used other template systems from different languages or frameworks you will find a lot of similarities in go templates.
This document is a brief primer on using go templates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Hugo</title>
      <link>/blog/hugoisforlovers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/hugoisforlovers/</guid>
      <description>Step 1. Install Hugo Goto hugo releases and download the appropriate version for your os and architecture.
Save it somewhere specific as we will be using it in the next step.
More complete instructions are available at installing hugo
Step 2. Build the Docs Hugo has its own example site which happens to also be the documentation site you are reading right now.
Follow the following steps:
 Clone the hugo repository Go into the repo Run hugo in server mode and build the docs Open your browser to http://localhost:1313  Corresponding pseudo commands:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrate to Hugo from Jekyll</title>
      <link>/blog/migrate-from-jekyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/migrate-from-jekyll/</guid>
      <description>Move static content to static Jekyll has a rule that any directory not starting with _ will be copied as-is to the _site output. Hugo keeps all static content under static. You should therefore move it all there. With Jekyll, something that looked like
▾ &amp;lt;root&amp;gt;/ ▾ images/ logo.png  should become
▾ &amp;lt;root&amp;gt;/ ▾ static/ ▾ images/ logo.png  Additionally, you&amp;rsquo;ll want any files that should reside at the root (such as CNAME) to be moved to static.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 1- Beyoncé vs Solange: Which Knowles Sister is More Likely to Make You Get Up and Groove? by Gianeen Magno </title>
      <link>/project1gbm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project1gbm/</guid>
      <description>0.) Introduction The datasets that I have chosen are the audio features of Beyoncé Knowles and Solange Knowles’ tracks that are available on Spotify, specifically, their solo discographies that are studio albums and non-special edition. This dataset was tediously acquired by installing the package “spotifyr” and utilizing “Spotify for Developers” on Spotify’s website, as well as spending a/n (large) amount of time figuring out how to use Spotify’s API. I mainly decided to do this because I’ve always wondered how Spotify develops music suggestions based on users’ listening histories, and it was very interesting to see that there are so many components that goes behind a track in order to curate a playlist- from “Your Daily Mix” to “Discover Weekly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2</title>
      <link>/project2gbm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project2gbm/</guid>
      <description>Just running some libraries
library(vegan) ## Loading required package: permute ## Loading required package: lattice ## This is vegan 2.5-6 library(zoo) ## ## Attaching package: &amp;#39;zoo&amp;#39; ## The following objects are masked from &amp;#39;package:base&amp;#39;: ## ## as.Date, as.Date.numeric library(lmtest) library(tidyverse) ## ── Attaching packages ───────── tidyverse 1.3.0 ── ## ✓ ggplot2 3.2.1 ✓ purrr 0.3.3 ## ✓ tibble 2.1.3 ✓ dplyr 0.8.5 ## ✓ tidyr 1.0.2 ✓ stringr 1.4.0 ## ✓ readr 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>/resume2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resume2020/</guid>
      <description>EDUCATION
The University of Texas at Austin • May 2020
• B.S.A. Biology, College of Natural Sciences
• B.A. Health and Society (Concentration: Health and the Economy), College of Liberal Arts
• Business of Healthcare Certificate, McCombs School of Business
EXPERIENCE
Osier Laboratory, Dell Medical School • May 2018-Present • Research Assistant
• Research barriers that prevent children from being admitted into emergency departments in order to devise ways that deconstruct parents’ hesitancies towards hospitals</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>