<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>gianeen</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on gianeen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Expressing Gratitude Using Python and R</title>
      <link>/blog/expressing-gratitude-using-python-and-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/expressing-gratitude-using-python-and-r/</guid>
      <description>So- you’re graduating in 13 days, you want to express some gratitude to the people you’ve met along the way during your past four years in college, and you have a project due in 5 days which requires you to demonstrate to your professor that you understand the value in and know how to execute using Python and R together.
Have no fear! Today I’m going to show you how you can do just that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2</title>
      <link>/project2gbm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project2gbm/</guid>
      <description>Just running some libraries
library(vegan) ## Loading required package: permute ## Loading required package: lattice ## This is vegan 2.5-6 library(zoo) ## ## Attaching package: &amp;#39;zoo&amp;#39; ## The following objects are masked from &amp;#39;package:base&amp;#39;: ## ## as.Date, as.Date.numeric library(lmtest) library(tidyverse) ## ── Attaching packages ──────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────── tidyverse 1.3.0 ── ## ✓ ggplot2 3.2.1 ✓ purrr 0.3.4 ## ✓ tibble 2.1.3 ✓ dplyr 0.8.5 ## ✓ tidyr 1.0.2 ✓ stringr 1.4.0 ## ✓ readr 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 1- Beyoncé vs Solange: Which Knowles Sister is More Likely to Make You Get Up and Groove? by Gianeen Magno </title>
      <link>/project1gbm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project1gbm/</guid>
      <description>0.) Introduction The datasets that I have chosen are the audio features of Beyoncé Knowles and Solange Knowles’ tracks that are available on Spotify, specifically, their solo discographies that are studio albums and non-special edition. This dataset was tediously acquired by installing the package “spotifyr” and utilizing “Spotify for Developers” on Spotify’s website, as well as spending a/n (large) amount of time figuring out how to use Spotify’s API. I mainly decided to do this because I’ve always wondered how Spotify develops music suggestions based on users’ listening histories, and it was very interesting to see that there are so many components that goes behind a track in order to curate a playlist- from “Your Daily Mix” to “Discover Weekly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>Projects Here are my coding projects that I completed for Computational Biology class at UT during my Spring 2020 semester:
  Exploratory Data Analysis with Tidyverse Tools: Beyoncé versus Solange
  Modeling, Testing, and Classification of Beyoncé and Solange&amp;rsquo;s Music
  BIG thank you to Nathaniel for taking time outside of lecture to help me learn how to use Spotify&amp;rsquo;s API! Because of him and the opportunity to learn more about my interests in this class through the art of coding, my curiosity on how Spotify works has been fulfilled and I know so much more about Spotify&amp;rsquo;s algorithm behind-the-scenes for its users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>About: Hey there! My name is Gianeen. I&amp;rsquo;m a Chipotle connoisseur, avid R&amp;amp;B music listener, and a proud dog mom to two mixed Shih Tzus- Buddy (12) and Benji (7). I happily split my time in between Austin and Houston (H-town hold it down)! I will be graduating this May from The University of Texas at Austin with a Bachelor of Science and Arts in Biology, a Bachelor of Arts in Health and Society (with a concentration in Health and the Economy), and a Business of Healthcare certificate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>/resume2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resume2020/</guid>
      <description>EDUCATION
The University of Texas at Austin • May 2020
• B.S.A. Biology, College of Natural Sciences
• B.A. Health and Society (Concentration: Health and the Economy), College of Liberal Arts
• Business of Healthcare Certificate, McCombs School of Business
EXPERIENCE
Osier Laboratory, Dell Medical School • May 2018-Present • Research Assistant
• Research barriers that prevent children from being admitted into emergency departments in order to devise ways that deconstruct parents’ hesitancies towards hospitals</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>